Let me the explain the reasoning that I use when I
look at a new layout. It looks like there's two equally spaced
columns here. That signals to me we need linear layout weights,
where each of these have equal weights. So let's create a horizontal
linear layout. Within this first chart, we have three vertically stacked
text views, so we have a vertical linear layout, and the same
goes for this second chart with has two elements vertically stacked
on top of each other, which means we use a vertical linear
layout as well. And here's the code, we created a
new list item forecasts today XML file under the layout folder.
The code looks very similar to list item forecast. I
has a horizontal linear layout, as a root element. The first
channel is a vertical linear layout with the width zero
and a weight of one. The second child is another vertical
linear layout with a width of zero and a weight
of one, that way the horizontal space will be distributed evenly
among each child. If you go back to the first
linear layout, notice that we have three text views within
it. For date, high temperature, and low temperature. We specify
gravity to be center horizontal. So anything within the linear
layout will be centered horizontally. Otherwise, by default, they would
be left aligned to the linear layout. The same applies
for the second linear layout. We specify gravity to be
center horizontal so that the icon and the weather forecast
text view within it are also centered horizontally.